welcome to game theory online I'm Kevin
欢迎来到在线游戏理论，我是Kevin
Leighton Brown I'm one of the three
礼顿·布朗我是三者之一
instructors for this course the other
本课程的讲师
two are Matt Jackson and yohave shoham
两个是Matt Jackson和yohave shoham
both from Stanford University you'll see
都来自斯坦福大学
them both in subsequent videos this
他们都在随后的视频中
video is going to give you a high-level
视频将为您带来高层次的体验
sense of what game theory is all about
对博弈论的全部了解
and the kinds of concepts that we're
以及我们所涉及的概念
going to think about in the rest of the
在其余的部分要考虑
course first of all before I go on let
当然，首先我继续
me tell you a little bit more about what
我告诉你更多有关
game theory isn't game theory doesn't
博弈论不是博弈论不是
use the word game in the way that most
以大多数方式使用文字游戏
of us are used to in common life and it
我们中的人习惯于共同的生活
certainly doesn't think particularly
当然不是特别想
about computer games instead game theory
关于计算机游戏而非游戏理论
is a way of thinking about strategic
是一种思考战略的方式
interactions between self-interested
利己之间的互动
people for this reason it's very
人们因为这个原因
important for economics and also for
对于经济学以及对
computer science political science
计算机科学政治学
psychology and a variety of other
心理学和其他各种
disciplines what ties all of these
约束所有这些东西
disciplines together is a concern for
学科在一起是一个值得关注的问题
thinking about how self-interested
考虑如何自私
participants would behave in strategic
参与者会表现出战略性
interactions and also thinking about how
互动，并思考如何
those interactions should be structured
这些互动应该结构化
for example by a government or by the
例如由政府或
designer of a computer system in order
按顺序设计计算机系统
to lead to good outcomes I'm going to
导致好的结果，我要
begin by thinking about one such example
首先考虑一个这样的例子
from computer science this is an example
从计算机科学这是一个例子
that involves networking but don't be
涉及网络，但不要
scared off by the computer science
被计算机科学吓到
content it isn't representative of what
满足并不代表什么
will come in the rest of the course and
将在本课程的其余部分中进行
in any case I'm not going to assume that
无论如何，我不会假设
you have any particular knowledge about
您对任何特定知识
how computers work in this example I'm
在这个例子中计算机是如何工作的
going to begin by thinking about this
首先要考虑这个
pop up which you might have seen in your
弹出您可能已经在您的
browser before and if you're like most
浏览器之前，如果您最喜欢
people you realize that a pop-up in your
人们，您意识到您的弹出窗口
browser that promises slow connection
浏览器保证连接缓慢
detected click Next to correct maybe
检测到单击下一步以更正
shouldn't be trusted it might install a
不应该被信任，它可能会安装一个
virus or otherwise harm your computer so
病毒或以其他方式损害您的计算机，因此
you probably wouldn't click on this but
您可能不会单击此按钮，但是
the interesting thing is if you did this
有趣的是，如果您这样做
particular pop-up might actually help
特定的弹出窗口实际上可能会有所帮助
you I'd like to think about how it works
你我想考虑一下它是如何工作的
and we can use this example to
我们可以用这个例子来
illustrate something interesting
说明一些有趣的事情
game theory before I do that I need to
博弈论之前，我需要
tell you a little bit about how the TCP
告诉你一些关于TCP如何
protocol works which is one of the
协议的工作原理之一
backbones of the internet so as you
互联网的骨干，就像你一样
probably know if you're over here on the
大概知道你是否在这里
internet and you want to communicate
互联网，你想交流
with some other computer which is over
与其他已经结束的计算机
here what happens is that your
在这里发生的是你的
communication gets broken up into a
沟通分解成一个
bunch of different packets which
一堆不同的数据包
conceptually are kind of like envelopes
从概念上讲就像信封
with a message inside them that get
里面有一条消息
delivered across the network to your
通过网络传送到您的
recipient and when I say delivered
收件人，当我说交付时
across the internet I mean you don't
在互联网上，我是说你不
actually have a direct connection
实际上有直接联系
between your computer and your desired
在您的计算机和您想要的之间
recipient instead there's a whole
收件人反而有一个整体
sequence of different computers along
不同计算机的顺序
the way who pass the message one to the
将消息传递给一个的方式
next to get it from you to your
接下来将它从您那里拿到您的
recipient so you pass the network the
收件人，以便您通过网络
message along the network to some
网络上的一些消息
computer you're connected to it passes
您连接的计算机通过
it to another computer and so on down
它到另一台计算机，依此类推
the chain until it reaches your
链，直到到达你
recipient at that point your recipient
那时的收件人
sees that the message is addressed to it
看到邮件已发送给它
and it sends back an acknowledgment to
然后将确认发送回
you telling you that it received the
您告诉您它收到了
message and that acknowledgment likewise
消息和确认同样
passes through a whole sequence of
通过整个序列
computers until it gets back to you
电脑，直到它回到你身边
so far so good here's the catch
到目前为止，这很好
sometimes a computer in the Internet is
有时互联网上的计算机是
overwhelmed with messages let's say this
不知所措让我们这样说
one right here and when that happens it
一个就在这里，什么时候发生
handles this congestion in a pretty
漂亮地处理这种拥挤
surprising way it takes some of the
令人惊讶的方式需要一些
messages that it receives and it just
它收到的消息，它只是
throws them away and it doesn't tell
把它们扔掉，这并不能说明
anyone it just deletes the messages
任何人只要删除邮件
until it gets down to a level that it
直到下降到它的水平
can handle again and then with the stuff
可以再处理一次
that it can handle again it continues
它可以再次处理它继续
behaving as it should passing messages
行为应传递消息
on appropriately well you might wonder
在适当的情况下，您可能会怀疑
then how it is that you end up with
那你最终会怎么样
reliable communication over the Internet
互联网上可靠的通讯
given that every now and then some
鉴于每时每刻
computer on the internet throws away
互联网上的计算机会丢弃
your messages
您的留言
well the way that this works is that
运作良好的方式是
your computer waits a certain amount of
您的计算机等待一定数量的
time after sending a message to see if
发送消息后的时间以查看是否
it gets an acknowledge
得到承认
and if it doesn't it assumes that the
如果不是，则假定
message was never received and sends it
消息从未收到并发送
again here's the part that's important
再次，这是重要的部分
for our discussion of game theory your
对于我们对博弈论的讨论
computer also does something else in
电脑还可以做其他事情
this situation it slows down the speed
这种情况会减慢速度
at which it continues to send messages
它继续发送消息
in the future on the assumption that
在未来的假设
there's some congestion somewhere in the
在某处有些拥挤
network and that this congestion can be
网络，这种拥塞可能是
reduced by bombarding the network with
通过轰炸网络减少
fewer messages per unit time and
单位时间内的消息更少，并且
likewise other computers on the Internet
互联网上的其他计算机
are doing the same thing that's why we
在做同样的事情，这就是为什么我们
don't have the network completely
没有完全的网络
saturated that's why most of the time we
这就是为什么大多数时候我们饱和的原因
get pretty reasonable throughput on the
获得相当合理的吞吐量
internet because everybody is balancing
互联网，因为每个人都在平衡
the speed that they send messages out
他们发送消息的速度
using what's called this back off
使用所谓的这种退缩
mechanism in the TCP protocol okay
TCP协议中的机制还可以
that's all you need to know about the
这就是您需要了解的所有信息
back off mechanism I'd like to think
退缩机制我想
about the strategic problem that you
关于你的战略问题
face in deciding whether to install this
面对决定是否安装这个
somewhat suspicious-looking piece of
看起来有些可疑
software that is I'd like to ask should
我想问的软件应该
you send your packets on your network
您在网络上发送数据包
connection using a correctly implemented
使用正确实现的连接
version of the TCP protocol which does
TCP协议的版本
have the back off mechanism inside it or
内部有退避机制，或者
should you run this program and instead
你应该运行这个程序，而不是
use a defective implementation which
使用有缺陷的实现
disables the back off mechanism and just
禁用退避机制，只是
blasts the network all the time without
无时无刻不在炸毁网络
any concern for the congestion that it
担心它的拥挤
will cause other people or you well this
会导致其他人或你很好
is a bit of a surprising use of language
有点令人惊讶的语言用法
but problems like this one are what game
但是像这样的问题是什么游戏
theorists called games a game in general
理论家一般将游戏称为游戏
is any interaction between two or more
是两个或多个之间的任何交互
people where the outcomes of the
人们在哪里
interaction depend on what everybody
互动取决于每个人
does and everybody has different levels
确实，每个人都有不同的水平
of happiness for the different outcomes
不同结果带来的幸福感
so let's think about a two-player
让我们考虑一个两人游戏
version of this interaction which a game
这个互动的版本是哪个游戏
theorist would call a two-player game
理论家会称之为两人游戏
you might incidentally worry that the
您可能会偶然地担心
Internet has a lot more than two people
互联网不止两个人
using it and so that this two-player
使用它，这样这两个玩家
restriction is going to be a problem
限制将是一个问题
you'll have to trust me but this example
你必须相信我，但是这个例子
scales very naturally to larger numbers
很自然地扩展到更大的数字
of players and everything interesting
玩家和所有有趣的事物
about it would remain true so in the
关于它会保持真实，所以在
two-player case we have a question of
两人游戏，我们有一个问题
whether each of the players should use a
每个玩家是否应该使用
correct implementation whether one of
正确的实施是否之一
them will use a correct implementation
他们将使用正确的实现
and the other one a defective
另一个是有缺陷的
implementation or whether both of them
实施还是两者
will use defective implementations in
将在中使用有缺陷的实现
the case so we so we need to say what
这样的话，所以我们需要说什么
happens in order to analyze this let's
为了分析这一点，让我们
say that when both players use correct
说当两个玩家都使用正确的
implementations they both experience a
他们都经历过的实现
delay of one millisecond let's say that
延迟一毫秒让我们说
if one person uses a correct
如果一个人使用正确的
implementation and the other person uses
实施和其他人使用
a defective one then the person with the
一个有缺陷的人，然后与
defective implementation manages to
有缺陷的实施设法
flood the network with packets in a way
数据包以某种方式泛洪网络
that causes the other person to back off
导致其他人退缩
pretty heavily causing the person who
造成很大的人
backed off to experience a much longer
退缩以体验更长的时间
delay and the person with the defective
延误和有缺陷的人
implementation to get their packets
实现获取他们的数据包
through virtually immediately lastly
最后几乎通过
let's say that if both people use
假设如果两个人都使用
defective implementations of TCP then
TCP的有缺陷的实现
we're again in a symmetric situation
我们又处于对称状态
where they both experience the same
他们都经历相同的地方
delay and they both experience a bigger
延迟，他们都经历更大
delay than they would have before
比以前延迟
because there's now a greater chance
因为现在有更大的机会
that their packets will be lost at every
他们的数据包将在每次丢失
stage in the chain and so it will take
链中的阶段，因此需要
them longer to send a message well I'd
他们更长的时间才能很好地发送信息
like to encourage you to play this game
喜欢鼓励你玩这个游戏
with a friend or to play it even just in
与朋友一起玩，甚至只是在里面玩
your head or best of all to play it on
发挥您的头或所有功能中最好的
the online system that we've provided
我们提供的在线系统
where you can interact with other
在这里您可以与其他人互动
students in the class what do I mean to
班上的学生我是什么意思
play a game well this game might not
玩一个好游戏，这个游戏可能不会
seem very exciting to play as compared
相比起玩起来似乎非常令人兴奋
to other things that you would call
其他你会打电话给的东西
games like soccer or chess but in
像足球或国际象棋这样的游戏，但是
principle all of these games are the
原则上所有这些游戏都是
same there are sets of actions that
同样，有一些动作
players can take and after everybody has
玩家可以接受，每个人都拥有
chosen what they're going to do in the
选择了他们将在
game there's some result where everybody
游戏有一些结果，每个人
feels at different levels of happiness
感到不同程度的幸福
this very simple game
这个非常简单的游戏
has each player choose either to use a
让每个玩家选择使用
correct implementation or to use a
正确执行或使用
defective implementation and once we
有缺陷的实施，一旦我们
know what both players will do we can
知道两位选手都会做什么
look at these rules that I've given here
看看我在这里给出的这些规则
and decide how happy both players would
并决定两位玩家的幸福程度
be of course nobody likes delay so the
当然是没人喜欢延迟，所以
players are trying to minimize the
玩家正在尝试最小化
amount of delay that they experience in
他们经历的延迟量
the network so if you wanted to minimize
网络，所以如果您想最小化
the amount of delay that you experienced
您经历的延迟量
how would you play this game that's kind
您将如何玩这种游戏
of the most natural question to think
要思考的最自然的问题
about when you're thinking about a game
关于何时考虑游戏
theoretic setting but I'd like to invite
理论背景，但我想邀请
you to think about a bunch of other more
你要考虑更多其他
abstract and philosophical questions
抽象和哲学问题
which we'll also address throughout this
我们还将在整个过程中解决
course first of all do you think it's
当然首先您认为这是
the case that all users should be
所有用户都应该
expected to behave the same in a
预期在
situation like this relatedly if you're
这样的情况，如果你是
not one of the players of the game but
不是游戏的玩家之一，而是
rather you're someone who cares about
而是你是一个关心的人
how the whole system works from the
整个系统如何从
outside
外
for example the designer of the network
例如网络的设计师
what kinds of global patterns of
什么样的全球格局
behavior would you expect to see emerge
您期望看到的行为
you'll notice that these numbers that I
您会注意到这些数字
came up with here are a little bit
想到这里有一点
arbitrary and they're not very precise
武断，不是很精确
it's reasonable to wonder how much these
有理由想知道这些多少
predictions that we can make about how
我们可以做出的预测
the game should be played and what
游戏应该玩什么
behavior would occur depend on those
行为将发生取决于那些
numbers is it the case that for slightly
数字是轻微的情况
different numbers we would expect to see
我们希望看到的不同数字
very different behavior what effect
行为截然不同有什么作用
would there be if players could
如果球员可以的话
communicate with each other before they
在彼此交流之前
played the game in a non binding way
以非约束性方式玩游戏
what effect would there be if players
如果玩家有什么影响
could repeatedly play the game against
可以反复对战
each other either for a finite number of
彼此之间的数量有限
repetitions or infinitely finally how
重复或无限地最终如何
important is it how I model my opponent
重要的是我如何塑造我的对手
is it different if I think my opponent
如果我认为我的对手有什么不同
is rational and does something that is
是理性的，做的是
in his or her own best interest or would
为了他或她自己的最大利益或
I play this game in the same way
我以相同的方式玩这个游戏
regardless of how I believe my opponent
不管我如何相信我的对手
is thinking about the game these are
在考虑游戏，这些是
examples of the kinds of questions that
这类问题的例子
this course will help you to think about
本课程将帮助您思考
and we'll offer you some answers to and
我们将为您提供一些答案，以及
the tcp back off game
tcp退场游戏
is just one example of a real-world
只是现实世界的一个例子
situation that we can examine using game
我们可以使用游戏检查的情况
theory throughout the course will
整个课程中的理论
describe many more real-world examples
描述更多真实的例子
that game theory can be used to think
博弈论可以用来思考
about thank you for joining us in this
谢谢您加入我们
course we hope you have a great
当然，我们希望您一切顺利
experience and we look forward to seeing
经验，我们期待看到
you in coming up videos bye-bye
你在视频再见